Gulbala Salamov



Software Developer

Nationality: Turkish, Azerbaijan

Personal Profile

I am a Software Developer with a Researcher background. I am passionate about using modern technologies and writing technical contents. I am positive minded, flexible individual enjoying working in both my own initiative and team. I always follow best practices improve myself.

Education

MSc, Computer Science 2014 – 2016 Swansea University, U.K.

BSc, Computer Education & Instructional Technologies 2010 – 2014 Middle East Technical University, Turkey

Professional Experience

Java Software Developer – Turkish Airlines, Turkey Feb 2023 –

- Working on the design, development and integration of Java and Spring backend, as well as JSF and PrimeFace for frontend applications
- Reviewing and maintaining applications to meet new requirements throughout the software life cycle

LowCode/NoCode Developer & Technical Writer - eSystems, Finland Feb 2022 - July 2022

- Building applications in OutSystems (LowCode Dev Environment)
- Creating high quality documentations

Android Developer & Researcher – University College London, U.K. Apr 2019 - Apr 2021

- Maintaining data collection app using Java and Android SDK
- Designing new UI interfaces
- Contributing to academic research and workshops

Contact

- +90 536 710 2202
- ¹ github.com/gulbalasalamov
- ² <u>linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov</u>
- ³ g.salamov@gmail.com

Languages

- TURKISH NATIVE
- AZERBAIJAN NATIVE
- ENGLISH BUSINESS
- RUSSIAN ELEMENTARY
- GERMAN BEGINNER

5 Words to Describe Me

- Problem solver
- Consistent
- Kind
- Positive
- Enthusiastic

Industry Experience

- Airline
- Education

Technical Writer - Level Publishing House, Turkey

Sep 2017 - Mar 2019

- Writing technical content for Android programming text book

Researcher (Intern) – State University of New York, U.S.A June 2017 - Sep 2017

- Building interactive prototypes for university's mobile app

Business Analyst - SIP Azerbaijan

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

- Communicating with clients and verifying their needs
- Simplifying complex technical concepts with high quality prototypes, use cases and diagrams

ICT Teacher (Intern) – Middle East Technical University, Turkey Sep 2013 - June 2014

- Teaching students to build algorithms to solve real life problems by playing logic based games
- Building simple apps using visual coding tools

Major Projects

Turkish Airlines Developer Portal

Description: A platform designed to facilitate the use of APIs provided by Turkish Airlines. The portal serves a gateway to their APIs allowing developers to enhance their applications with features related to flights, availability, promotion, airport infomation and so on. Link to source:

https://developer.apim.turkishairlines.com

Role: As a Java Developer, my role centered around designing and developing APIs for external parties, specifically promotional code usage and fare search. Here are the key highlights:

1. API Design and Deployment:

- Utilizing OpenAPI specifications, I configured our Promotion, Domestic Fare System (DFS), and International Fare System (IFS) API products within Apicurio Studio web based application.
- These APIs were then deployed Docker-like environment, ensuring scability and reliability.

2. Impact and Result

By implementing the RedHat 3Scale API Management product, I achieved significant results:

What Motivates Me

- Solving real life problems by building software solutions
- Researching and creating contents both educational and scientific
- Learning and sharing my knowledge



- Security: Robust authentication and authorization protocols helped the business to cut revenue lose by preventing attackers using webservices to create promotion code and coupons. Several Information Security Vulnerability Records closed as well.
- **Analytics:** Leveraging API management tools, the team gained visual user and service analytics.
- Documentation Efficiency: The automatic generation of API documentation directly from the design, ensured accuracy, and improved comminication with API consumers.

ECSAnVIs

Description: Extreme Citizen Science Analysis and Visualisation (ECSAnVis) is a five-year, €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC). The project aims to develop geographical analysis and visualization tools for non-literate communities and design culturally appropriate and aligned with specific needs of social practices of the target audiences.

Role: As a Java/Android developer, my work involved mobile application development, usability enhancements, and active participation in academic studies.

1. Mobile App Design and Development

- I maintained the data collection app called Sapeli, fixed bugs and introduced new features to enhance user experience.
- Following HCI practices, I designed and implemented interactive prototypes using digital tools and contributed to building Sapelli Visualiser app to show geographically meaningful collected data.

2. Impact and Result

My contributions helped society and improved the usability of tools:

- Community Engagement: The apps enabled local communities to actively participate in scientific data collection and increased scientific literacy among participants
- **Stable App Version:** Bug free, tested and more stable version of data collection app released.



A. PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java

Android

SQL, OracleSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Version CS (Git, Github, Bitbucket)

Testing Framework (Debugging, Junit5)

B. SERVER SIDE TECHNOLOGIES

Oracle WebLogic Server

Spring, Spring Boot

C. FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES

Language (CSS, HTML)

Framework (JSF, PrimeFace)

Prototype (AdobeXD, Figma)

D. OTHER SKILLS

OAS & Swagger

Low-Code & No-Code (OutSystems)

R & D, Academic Writings

Additional Tools (Jira, Confluence, Slack, Teams)

Certifications

IELTS Score: 6.5

2018

Books

Android Sanati - Android Mobile Programming Book

(Gulbala Salamov¹, Volkan Gurbuz²)

LEVEL Publishing House, Turkey (2017)

ISBN 6058352766

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html

Publications

A Novel Portable Nanotechnology Approach for Targeted Cancer Therapy

2nd International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies Innovative Technologies (2018)

Authors: Bunyatova, U., Kocum C., Haberal E., Salamov G.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8567302

New Strategy of Distance Education

Universal Journal of Educational Research, Horizon Research Publishing, USA (2014)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

http://www.hrpub.org/journals/article_info.php?aid=1578

Simulation Learning Based on Formal-Logical and Fuzzy Logics

6th International Computer and Instructional Technologies

Symposium, Turkey (2012)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://www.pegem.net/Akademi/kongre_detay.aspx?id=137107

Logic of Integrity, Fuzzy Logic and Knowledge Modelling For **Machine Education**

5th International Conference on Application of ICT, Azerbaijan (2011)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6110956



Professional Membership

European Cooperation in Science and Technology (COST) (2018 -)

Citizen Science Work Group Member

https://cs-eu.net/users/gulbalasalamov